## **Personal information**

**Firstname**: Elliot **Lastname**: Coene

**Birth date**: 19-08-1983

Locality: Waterloo (20 km of Brussels)

Nationality: Belgian

Actual status: Freelance

**VAT number**: BE 0821 228 922

**Usual hourly rate**: 50 €/h eVAT



#### Contacts:

E-mail: elliot.coene@e-telier.be
Phone: +32 4 76 85 73 06

Website: https://www.e-telier.be

#### **Summary:**

I've been a passionate professional developer since 2005.

During this period I had the chance to work on a wide variety of projects; softwares, websites, applications, video games, ...

Those accumulated experiences gave me the know-how and the trust needed to be given more and more responsabilities.

I'm used to be the link between an idea and its final realization, carrying out the technical aspects of a project from A to Z while communicating with each member of the team (clients, designers, project manager, ...).

# Skill set

### Specializations:

- Analyzing of a project technical needs
- · Server side programming with PHP
- Creation of project-optimized databases (SQL)
- Client side programming with Javascript and JQuery
- Layout translation in CSS3, HTML5

#### Other skills:

- · Graphical tools Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator and Flash
- Application development using Apache Cordova
- Knowledge of Git, Unity 3D, Actionscript 3 et Flex (Adobe Flash)

#### Languages:

Mother tongue: French

Foreign language	Reading	Writting	Listening	Speaking
English	4/5	4/5	4/5	3/5
Dutch	2/5	2/5	1/5	1/5

# Work experience

# **2010 – present**Freelance developer at E-telier

Development of numerous projects, mixing a wide range of responsibilities:

- Developer: Managing of the whole project creation following the client needs, demands and budget
- Web master: Maintaining a service and updating of a project
- Programmer:Translating a set of requests into concrete coding
- · Graphic integrator: Translating the static designers' ideas into interactive products

#### Some examples:

#### Delasia

#### 2018 - present

Development of an online plateform to create and manage the internal of a food company (orders, promotions, complains, requests, deliveries, ...).

There are 3 secured access types: admins, salesmen and clients, each with their own abilities.

This online system is then synchronized with their on location software (downward and upward).

#### Technologies:

PHP, MySQL, Javascript, JQuery, CSS3



#### **P&V F1 Simulator**

#### 2017 - 2018

Android application developed for the Brussels car show of 2018.

The purpose of this application was to regulate the queues for the simulator by playing a quiz and entering customer data.

The data was then automatically synchronized with the server and accessible to the salespeople at the end of the line.

#### Technologies:

Cordova, Javascript, PHP, MySQL



#### VRto.me

#### 2016 - present

Web application designed to allow VR professionals to create, update and manage their VR projects online.

To manage the heavy computing the projects generation is asynchronous, each new project modification enters a queue that is processed 24/7 following the subscription type of the user.

The e-commerce part is subscription based using the Fastspring service.

#### Technologies:

PHP, MySQL, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, KRPano



#### **AMI Project**

#### 2015 - present

This is an accounting and invoicing web application allowing its users to fully manage their business online.

It facilitates the workflow, from the first estimate to the final invoice, passing by the order form. All documents can be exported into PDF or CSV, they also can be printed or sent to the client using the included communication tools.

The e-commerce allows the user to buy different access types, it uses the Mollie payment service.

#### Technologies:

PHP, MySQL, Javascript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, TCPDF



#### Siemens Pluviorad

#### 2013 - 2017

I had to maintain and update an existing online application build with Flex.

This weather application was used by the SPW (Public Service of Wallonia) to study and manage watercouses, rivers, dams, rains.

Mainly it was the visual representation of the data collected, but it could do many more.

#### Technologies:

Flex, Actionscript 3, Java



#### JTI Slideshow

#### 2011 - 2012

Software developped to be displayed on TVs at the different company locations.

It presented information and data to the employee.

Each iteration of the software had to be synchronized with the data that was stored and managed within a centralized server.

#### Technologies:

PHP, MySQL, Adobe Director, Lingo



## 2006 - 2009

## **Lead programmer at Belle Productions**

Employed within the Belle Productions video game company as a lead programmer and technical supervisor on numerous projects.

#### I was in charge of:

- · building and maintaining the game engines
- lead the team of programmers
- · counseling the game designer
- · driving the graphic designers on technical issues
- · helping the integrators and level designers

#### Projects:

- Les Secrets d'Ombyliss (Video game 2008-2009)
- Belgacom Kid City: La Boite à idées (Software 2008)
- Trolls de Troy : La Citée de la Mort Rose (Video game 2007-2008)
- Intervilles : le jeu (Video game 2007)
- Patrimonia (Video game 2007)
- Franklin et le trésor du Lac (Video game 2006)

## 2005 - 2006

## Programmer at Atelier de la page

I was hired to develop an **e-commerce plateform** for local markets and producers.

The core concept was to create 3 types of access and content, each with their own capabilities:

- Admin: to manage the website and the sales
- Client: to buy products
- · Producer: to present and sell their products

# **Education**

# 2002 - 2005

## Multimedia Graduate at Institut des Arts de Diffusion

#### **Acquired skills:**

- Programming (PHP, Actionscript, Lingo, ...)
- 2D design (Adobe Phoptoshop, Illustrator, ...)
- 3D design (3DSMax)
- Video editing (Adobe Premiere)
- Sound editing

This wide range of skills has been a strong asset in communicating with the different members that make up a development team.

As an end-of-study project I developed a video game, working and supervising 4 designers.